

NICK MERRITT

ux + visual designer

PROFILE

I'm a digital designer who has spent the last 15 years honing my craft. I love solving design problems through research and user-centered design. I'm looking for a collaborative team where I can continue to learn and grow while contributing to a mission I believe in.

SKILLS

- UX Design
- Visual Design
- Design Systems
- ☐ Front-end Development
- Adobe Creative Suite
- ☐ Figma / Sketch
- ☐ HTML / CSS

EDUCATION

- The Art Institute of Atlanta
- Northwest Mississippi Community College

WORK EXPERIENCE

□ NZXT - MARCH 2021 - PRESENT Interactive Designer (DTC)

www.nzxt.com

My team is responsible for all UX and visual design across our website. I also act as lead designer for our BLD configurator experiences. I partner with our Research team to identify pain points, and collaborate closely with Product and Engineering to design concepts that improve UX.

☐ MIND RESEARCH INSTITUTE - JULY 2017 - JULY 2020 Design Manager

www.mindresearch.org / www.stmath.com

Our team was responsible for all marketing creative in addition to designing and maintaining multiple online products. My responsibilities included managing the design team at a higher, strategic level, while also contributing as lead designer. I built connections with other creative teams throughout the organization to encourage collaboration across multiple projects. I also mentored my team and helped create growth paths to ensure they were being challenged creatively.

- □ FREELANCE / CONTRACT JULY 2015 JULY 2017
- □ KITBASH BRAND DESIGN OCT 2013 JULY 2015
 Art Director / UX Designer
 www.getkitbashed.com

A small agency with big ideas. My focus at Kitbash was on branding, UX design and development. I worked with clients to help design a wide range of experiences including personal blogs, larger corporate sites, and ecommerce experiences.

THINK WEBSTORE - SEP 2010 - MAY 2014
Art Director / Senior Web Designer
www.thinkwebstore.com

Joining such a small team allowed me to gain experience in several different creative areas (web, social media, branding, advertising, etc.). I was able to use my experience to teach and push others creatively.

CONTACT

901.921.8398

mick@nick-merritt.com

www.nick-merritt.com

twitter.com/nick_merritt

in linkedin.com/in/nmerritt

dribbble.com/nickmerritt